When every college turned them down. . . they made one up.
Accepted is a comedy film directed by Steve Pink.
A high school slacker who's rejected by every school he applies to opts to create his own institution of higher
learning, the South Harmon Institute of Technology, on a rundown piece of property near his hometown.
Bartleby Gaines, played by Justin Long.
Sherman Schrader, played by Jonah Hill.
Monica Moreland, played by Blake Lively.
Glen, played by Adam Herschman.
Hands, played by Columbus Short.
Rory, played by Maria Thayer.
Accepted is a 2006 American comedy film directed by
Steve Pink, marking his directorial debut.
The screenplay was written by Adam Cooper, Bill Collage, and Mark Perez.
The film stars Justin Long, Blake Lively, Anthony
Heald and Lewis Black in lead roles.
The plot follows Bartleby Gaines, a high school graduate who, after being rejected by every college he applies to, concocts a
plan to create a fake university with his friends to convince his parents he's moving forward with his education.
As more students, also rejected from other schools, mistakenly apply to the fictional South Harmon Institute of
Technology (S.H.I.T.), Bartleby and his friends decide to run the school as if it were a real institution.
The film was released on August 18, 2006, and
received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of straitjacket ,
college, fraud, girlfriend, university.
The tone is lighthearted.